<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My bits</title>
    <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My bits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lpantano.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to plot miRNA, gene expression and functional analysis together</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2018-08-13-omic-figure-for-mirna-gene-functional-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2018-08-13-omic-figure-for-mirna-gene-functional-data/</guid>
      <description>This post should show you an easy way to get the following data type integrated into a figure:
 functional enrichment analysis gene expression data from any technology miRNA expression data from any technology  I am using the function isoNetwork from the package isomiRs, that of course is developed by me :) My ego is not that big, it is just I wanted a figure showing that information, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any at a time, but if you know any, tweet me about it to @lopantano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subset of object creates bigger RDA file size than original object</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2017-08-24-subset-object-creates-bigger-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 17:50:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2017-08-24-subset-object-creates-bigger-file/</guid>
      <description>This is a funny story, and I will try to tell you how I realized I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about R in 400 words.
I work at the Bioinformatic Core at Harvard TH School. People who know us, or collaborate with us, knows that we mainly use bcbio to analyze sequencing data (check it out, super cool tool).
Something that we are working on is to load the data after bcbio finishes into R to ease the downstream analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEGreport to plot nice RNA-seq figures</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2017-03-20-degreport-rnaseq-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 17:50:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2017-03-20-degreport-rnaseq-figures/</guid>
      <description>Differentially gene expression analysis with RNA-seq data is quite common nowadays, and there are pretty good Bioconductor packages for that: limma::voom, DESeq2 &amp;hellip;
The code for that part is quite simple, being super quick to get a list of de-regulated genes. However, downstream analyses vary a lot depending on the project itself. But I found myself doing the same plots and analyses many times for different project, so I put together a bunch of plots and analyses using code from my colleagues at work (@HSPH bioinformatics core) and myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA Annotation Tools Comparison</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2016-03-24-mirna-annotation-tools-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 19:49:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2016-03-24-mirna-annotation-tools-comparison/</guid>
      <description>In summary: I will show which is the best miRNA mapping tool. I used several options for this benchmarking:
 miraligner from SeqBuster suit (I am one of the authors) bowtie2 and bowtie novoalign from novocraft suit GEM srnabench microrazer STAR miRExpress  I think that these are the most used, and other not used but good to try them. They were clearly developed for other purposes, but as well, they generate the input of many miRNA pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>small RNA abundance [miss-] viz</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2013-10-29-small-rna-abundance-miss-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 08:05:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2013-10-29-small-rna-abundance-miss-viz/</guid>
      <description>My PhD was focused on small RNA sequencing data. I had a problem when I wanted to visualized the amount of small RNAs from the beginning. Here the problem, assume that you have a certain distribution of small RNA sequences abundance:
seq1: 1500 times
seq2: 3 times
seq3: 2 times
And you want to show the nucleotide composition of the first nucleotide. You can do it either counting the # of sequences (or abundance) in your set (1505) or the number of unique (different) sequences (3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lying factor in figures</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2013-08-07-lying-factor-in-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 11:36:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2013-08-07-lying-factor-in-figures/</guid>
      <description>What is the lying factor in figures?
It is the ratio between the difference of two numbers and the difference of the visualization of those two numbers. For instance:
You have two groups, each group is represented by 4 and 2. The difference between 4 and 2 is 2. Since &amp;ldquo;a picture is worth a thousand words&amp;rdquo;, someone decides to represents those groups in a figure (yes, in excel to make it worst):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miRNA annotation: complex scenarios</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2013-05-27-mirna-annotation-complex-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 10:13:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2013-05-27-mirna-annotation-complex-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>Everybody who is working with microRNA knows about miRBase, it was the first miRNA catalogue. Everybody is using it to annotate small RNA sequences as miRNA or not. And it is great, and very helpfully&amp;hellip;but there are some cases that we should investigate our results.
For instance, what happens with miR-1246? it is a recent miRNA, primate specific, detected by sequencing in different studies (1,2,3). The counts related to these sequences are not so high, actually very low after normalization, but still are there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>visualizing small RNA mapping complexity</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2012-09-18-visualizing-small-rna-mapping-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 12:10:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2012-09-18-visualizing-small-rna-mapping-complexity/</guid>
      <description>I spent all my PhD working with small RNA sequences data. The main problem was, always those sequences that map in multiple locations, also denominated ambiguous sequences. From the very beginning, this made that pipelines remove this kind of sequences from the analysis, because you cannot assign them a unique location in the genome. But these sequences are interesting to study, since many of them change in size, for instance. This complexity is due to repeats in the genome and the scenario I am talking about here it is shown in the following figure: Each color it would be a different sRNA, and the lines show the locations of each sRNA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing science is also cool @polychart</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2012-08-14-visualizing-science-is-also-cool-polychart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 15:28:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2012-08-14-visualizing-science-is-also-cool-polychart/</guid>
      <description>One of my interest in science is finding new ways to visualize Big Data. Scientist are used to work with static visualization, that of course, is wonderful in the majority of the case. But it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be better dynamic visualization for exploration? Play with your data, explore, and finally when you get that great figure that tell you everything you was looking for, you can export it to an image portable format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bionformatics evolution 2005-2012</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2012-04-13-bionformatics-evolution-2005-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 10:45:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2012-04-13-bionformatics-evolution-2005-2012/</guid>
      <description>How much keywords in bioinformatics has changed in the past 7 years?
I did a small and quick experiment. I took the abstract of the papers published in Bioinformatics during Jan-2005 and during Jan-2012. Then I represented the words according to their frequency with the wordle tool. And the result was:
    What is main difference? There are new concepts, of course, but the main difference is the size of the word DATA and the word METHOD, as it happens in the real world, data increased a lot, so we put it much more in our work, and we need a lof of new methods, so we highlight this in our work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get colors for your heatmap annotation</title>
      <link>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2018-09-21-colors-for-annotations-for-heatmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lpantano.github.io/post/legacy/2018-09-21-colors-for-annotations-for-heatmaps/</guid>
      <description>This post will show how to configure quickly the colors for the annotation of rows/columns that go on top or on the side of a heatmap.
I normally use pheatmap a lot. Recently I discovered ComplexHeatmap. In both cases I spend always sometime changing the colors of the annotations. I ended up coding a function inside my package DEGreport to do that.
Given a data.frame with metadata data information will do:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>